Guide to the Frank Baker papers, 1641-2002 and undated, bulk 1740-1995 RL.00069
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Subject Files Series, 1641-1999 and undated, 122 boxes
  - Subject Files Series: Alphabetical Files, Sequence I Subseries, 1641-1996 and undated, 58 boxes
    - Handel, G. F., 1992 and undated (Box 81)
    - Handel, G.F. and Wesleys, 1953-1959, 1985 (Box 81)
    - Handwriting, Reading Medieval to 17th Century, 1957, 1972-1973, 1979, and undated (Box 81)
    - Handy, Thomas William, 1959 (Box 81)
    - Hannah, John, 1838-1865, and undated (Box 81)
    - Hanson, Thomas, 1780-1782 (Box 81)
    - Hardwick, Thomas, undated (Box 81)
    - Hardy, R. Spence, 1868 and undated (Box 81)
    - Hare, Edward, 1818, 1821, 1911, 1978, 1992, and undated (Box 81)
    - Harris, Howell, 1741, 1917-1928, 1968-1992, and undated (Box 81)
    - Harrogate, 1958 (Box 81)
    - Hartley Victoria College, 1949 (Box 81)
    - Hartley, Thomas, 1755, 1986, and undated (Box 81)
    - Haskins, Thomas, undated (Box 81)
    - Hatcher, Stephen, 1988, 1990, 1993 (Box 81)
    - Hauge, Hans Nielsen and JW, 1837, 1955 (Box 81)
    - Haughton, John, 1969 (Box 81)
    - Haverfordwest, 1960 (Box 81)
    - Haweis, Rev. Thomas, 1761, 1947-1951, and undated (Box 81)
    - Haworth, 1738-1770, 1837, 1850, 1853, 1981, and undated (Box 82)
    - Hawthorne, 1956 (Box 82)
    - Hay Family, 1951 (Box 82)
    - Hayman, J.G., 1960 (Box 82)
    - Heaton Collection, 1947-1958 and undated (Box 82)
    - Hebrew, 1808, 1980, and undated (Box 82)
    - Heck, Barbara, 1955, 1979 (Box 82)
    - Heitzenrater, Richard, Wesley and the People Called Methodists, 1990, 1991, 1995, and undated (Box 82)
    - Hell, 1983 (Box 82)
    - Henderson, John, 1793 and undated (Box 82)
    - Henry, Matthew, 1694, 1989, and undated (Box 82)
    - Heraldry, 1949-1951 and undated (Box 82)
    - Herbert, George, notes on JW's use of The Temple, circa 1730-1779, 1936-1987 (Box 82)
    - Herring, Thomas, 1892 and undated (Box 82)
    - Herschel, John, 1958 (Box 82)
    - Hervey, James, 1739, 1751, 1757, 1760, 1765, 1812, 1946-1957, 1969, and undated (Box 82)
    - Hickling, John, 1949, 1958, and undated (Box 82)
    - Higginson, Henry, 1951 (Box 82)
    - Hill, Richard, David, and Rowland, 1773, 1884, 1962, and undated (Box 82)
    - Hodges, John, undated (Box 82)
    - Hogarth, William, 1959, 1993, and undated (Box 82)
    - Holidays, 1952-1959 and undated (Box 82)
    - Holiness, 1939-1958, 1972-1974, 1983-1986, and undated (Box 83)
    - Holland and JW -- J. Van den Berg: John Wesley's Contacten Met Nederland, 1971, 1983 (Box 83)
    - Holland, Arthur, 1882-1930 (Box 83)
    - Holland, William, 1750 (Box 83)
    - Holmes, Elizabeth, 1730s, 1939, and undated (Box 83)
    - Holy Club, 1947 (Box 83)
    - Honor, Charles Garton, 1904, 1955, and undated (Box 83)
    - Honoraria, 1979 (Box 83)
    - Hoole, Elijah, 1830-1833, 1842, 1854-1855, 1863, and undated (Box 83)
      Photocopied extracts of manuscript diary of Elijah Hoole, missionary to India. Extracts cover circa 1830-1833, when he had returned to England.
    - Hopper, Christopher, 1762-1803, 1921, 1988 (Box 83)
    - Horton, John, 1772 (Box 83)
    - Hosier, Harry, 1983 and undated (Box 83)
    - Hospitals, 1948, 1958, and undated (Box 83)
    - Hotham, 1918 (Box 83)
    - Hotham, Sir Charles and Lady Gertrude, 1759 and undated (Box 83)
    - Howard, John, undated (Box 83)
    - Huddersfield, 1952 (Box 83)
    - Hudleston, 1752 (Box 83)
    - Hudson, George, 1756 (Box 83)
    - Hughes, Hugh Price, H. Maldwyn, 1883-1903, 1917-1923, 1959, and undated (Box 83)
    - Hull, 1841, 1844, 1885, 1893-1895, 1906, 1949-1964, 1970, 1977, and undated (Box 83)
    - Humberstone, 1948-1953 (Box 83)
    - Humphreys, Joseph, 1741, 1743, 1884, 1977-1978, 1987, and undated (Box 83)
    - Hunt, John and Joseph, 1838, 1853, 1952-1953 and undated (Box 83)
    - Hunting, 1945-1947 (Box 83)
    - Huntingdon, Lady, 1718, 1747, 1763-1787, 1840, 1882, 1897, 1915, 1940-1962, 1967, 1970, 1989, and undated (Box 83)
    - Huntington, William, 1856 and undated (Box 84)
    - Hutchings, John, 1730, 1737-1738, 1752-1753 (Box 84)
    - Hutton family, 1738-1774, 1947, and undated (Box 84)
    - Hykings, John, undated (Box 84)
    - Hymn Index, 1780, 1876, 1983, 1986, and undated (Box 84)
    - Hymnology: tune, 1749-1781, 1901, 1922, 1924, 1941, 1969-1970, 1984, and undated (Box 84)
    - Hymns, 1848, 1865, 1903, 1930-1933, 1946-1988, and undated, 3 folders (Box 84)
    - Illustrations, 1951 (Box 84)
    - Ince, Henry, 1972 (Box 84)
    - Independent Methodists, 1948, undated (Box 84)
    - Independent Study and Research, 1978 (Box 85)
    - Indexes, 1870s, 1981, undated (Box 85)
    - India, 1947 (Box 85)
    - Indians, American, 1977 (Box 85)
    - Ingham, Rev. Benjamin, 1737-40, 1951-1966 (Box 85)
    - Inghamites, 1760, 1902, 1952 (Box 85)
    - Insurance, 1893, 1976 (Box 85)
    - International, Methodist Historical Union, 1946-1947, and undated (Box 85)
    - Invitations (ministerial), 1949-1950 (Box 85)
    - Ireland, 1778, 1849, 1864-1865, 1911-1913, 1943-1956, 1977, and undated, 2 folders (Box 85)
    - Isaac, Daniel, 1809, 1814 (Box 85)
    - Islam Muslims, 1985 (Box 85)
    - Italian Methodism, 1985 (Box 85)
    - Italics, 1992 (Box 85)
    - Itinerant Minstry -- E. Dale Dunlap: The United Methodist System of Itinerant Ministry: Its Nature and Future, 1980 (Box 85)
    - Jaco, Peter, 1761-1971, 1967-1970 (Box 85)
    - James Family (Bristol), 1770s (Box 85)
    - James, John, H., 1857-1858, 1870, and undated (Box 85)
    - Japan, 1963-1978, 1990, 1971 (Box 85)
    - Jarratt, Devereux -- Steven Morgan: Lighting the Fire of American Methodism: Devereux Jarratt's Fostering Relationship with the Early American Methodists, 1973 (Box 85)
    - Jarratt, Devereux, Morgan on, 1930, 1973 (Box 85)
    - Jehovah's Witnesses, 1947, 1951, 1955 (Box 85)
    - Jenkins, E.E., 1964 (Box 85)
    - Jews, 1947, 1952 (Box 86)
    - Jigsaw Puzzle, undated (Box 86)
    - Jobson, F.J., 1858-1878, 1961 and undated (Box 86)
    - John Smith, undated (Box 86)
    - Johnson, Dr. Samuel, 1891, 1977, 1988-1989 and undated (Box 86)
    - Johnson, John/Robert/Thomas, 1764-1798, 1950, 1960 (Box 86)
    - Johnson, Joseph, undated (Box 86)
    - Jones, James, 1901 (Box 86)
    - Jones, John and Sara (or Sally), 1743-1770 (Box 86)
    - Jones, Robert and Thomas, 1745-1787, 1954 (Box 86)
    - Jones, Robert of Fonmar, 1901, 1953, and undated (Box 86)
    - Journals, 1972 (Box 86)
    - Joy, J.R., 1787, 1808, 1946 (Box 86)
    - Joyce, Matthias, 1786 (Box 86)
    - Judaism: Last Judgement, 1929 (Box 86)
    - Keeling, Isaac, 1850-1856 (Box 86)
    - Keighley, 1766, 1880-1944, and undated, 2 folders (Box 86)
    - Kelly, Charles H., undated (Box 86)
    - Kendall, George, 1931-1932 (Box 86)
    - Kent, Lewisham, 1880, 1949-1959 (Box 86)
    - Kenton, 1786 (Box 86)
    - Kershaw, John, 1766-1855, undated (Box 86)
    - Kidd, Tom--Hymn-books, 1974-1975 (Box 86)
    - Kilham, Alexander, 1792, 1957 and undated (Box 86)
    - Kinchin, Charles, 1901 (Box 86)
    - King's Preachers, 1767, 1971, 1986, and undated (Box 86)
    - Kingswood School, 1771-1790, 1948-1977 (Box 86)
    - Kingswood Wesleyana, 1937, 1983, and undated (Box 86)
    - Kline, Larry, circa 1995 (Box 87)
    - Knox, Alex, 1757-1831,1978 (Box 87)
    - Lampe, Hymns on the Great Festivals, 1994-1996 (Box 87)
    - Lamplough Collection, 1763, 1788, 1929, 1948-1951, and undated (Box 87)
    - Lancashire, 1808, 1924, 1950, 1955-1959, and undated (Box 87)
    - Lavington, Bishop George, undated (Box 87)
    - Law, 1987, undated (Box 87)
    - Law, William, 1729-1732, 1759, 1962, 1983 (Box 87)
    - Laymen, 1950 (Box 87)
    - Leake, James, 1730s, 1740s (Box 87)
    - Lectures, 1966 (Box 87)
    - Lee, Peter, 1958 (Box 87)
    - Lee, Thomas, undated (Box 87)
    - Leeds, 1946-1959, 1988 (Box 87)
      Includes pamphlet A Kindled Fire: John and Charles Wesley, and the Methodist Revival in the Leeds Area, by Peter Forsaith, 1988.
    - Leeds, 1988 (Box 87)
    - Leesburg, 1979-1988 (Box 87)
    - Leete, Frederick DeLand, 1736, 1766, 1769, 1775, 1784, 1930, 1946-1956, and undated, 2 folders (Box 87)
    - Lefevre, 1961 and undated (Box 87)
    - Legal Disputes, 1823, 1921-1923, and undated (Box 87)
    - Leicestershire, 1905, 1948-1950, and undated (Box 87)
    - Lending, 1770s, 1838, 1876, 1960 (Box 87)
    - Lessey, Theophiles, 1823-1835, and undated (Box 88)
    - Lending Fund, undated (Box 88)
    - Letter Reading, 1725, 1745 (Box 88)
    - Lettsom, Dr. John, 1744-1815, undated (Box 88)
    - Levick, Samuel, 1866 (Box 88)
    - Lewis, undated (Box 88)
    - Lewisham, 1749-1782 (Box 88)
    - Library: Duke, 1739, 1744, 1783-1785, 1961-1973, 1991, and undated (Box 88)
      Includes FB's provenance notes and transcriptions of various items in the following Rubenstein Library collections in Wesleyan and Methodist studies: Adam Clarke Papers, ca. 1762-1832; E. R. Hendrix Papers, 1764-1914; and Wesley Family Papers, 1726-1889.
    - Lightcliffe, 1910 and undated (Box 88)
    - Lincolnshire, 1936-1972 and undated (Box 88)
    - Lincolnshire Diocesan archives: Methodist treasures in, 1750-1770, 1812-1851, 1946-1967, 1987, 2 folders (Box 88)
    - Lincolnshire, Grimsby Circuit Society Record, 1769-1782,1988 (Box 88)
    - Literary Prizes, undated (Box 88)
    - Little, C. Deane, 1944-1947 (Box 88)
    - Little, James MSS, 1867 (Box 88)
    - Littlehales, 1772 (Box 88)
    - Liverpool, 1861, 1863, 1881, 1924, 1953-1958, 2 folders (Box 88)
    - Livingstone, David, 1920-1929, 1964, 2 folders (Box 88)
    - Lloyd, Samuel, 1760, 1947, undated (Box 88)
    - Local Histories, 1967 (Box 88)
    - Local Preachers, 1808, 1840, 1910, 1941-1957, and undated (Box 89)
    - London, 1738, 1943-1956, 1981, and undated (Box 89)
    - London, 1740-1805, undated (Box 89)
    - London Pilgrim, 1739, 1799, 1876, 1913, 1926-1933, 1949-1960, and undated (Box 89)
    - London: Foundery, 1740, 1776, 1781, 1859, 1937, 1976 (Box 89)
    - London: Wesley's Chapel, 1930, 1938, 1945-1958, 1974-1978, and undated (Box 89)
    - Lord's Supper, 1895, 1964-1971, 1987, and undated (Box 89)
    - Loughborough, 1965 (Box 89)
    - Louth, undated (Box 89)
    - Lovefeast, 1949-1951, undated (Box 89)
    - Lovefeasts, 1700s, 1832, 1873, 1956, 1984-1988, undated (Box 89)
    - Lovefeasts 1, 1956-1970 (Box 90)
    - Lovefeasts 2, 1930, 1949-1957, and undated (Box 90)
    - Lovefeasts 3, 1761, 1946-1960, 1970-1988, and undated, 2 folders (Box 90)
    - Lowdell, 1945 (Box 90)
    - Lowes, Matthew, 1774, 1795 (Box 90)
    - Lowther, undated (Box 90)
    - Loxdale, Anne, 1779, 1799, 1944 (Box 90)
    - Ludlow, 1952 (Box 90)
    - Lyte, Henry Francis, 1939, 1947, and undated (Box 90)
    - Macarius, Influence on JW, 1721, 1736, 1981, 1989 and undated (Box 90)
    - Macclesfield Circuit, 1786-1788 (George Story Papers, vol. 7), 1786-1788 and undated (Box 90)
    - MacDonald Family, 1844, 1868-1873, 1888, 1899-1910, 1920, 1956-1959 (Box 90)
    - Madan, Martin (1726-1790), 1749, 1757, 1780, 1851, 1983, and undated (Box 90)
      Notes; printed material; microfilm (inverse negative) printout of Madan letter to John Wesley and typewritten transcription of same, 1749 Dec. 18; also transcriptions of letters to George Whitefield, 1757, and Charles Wesley, 1780.
    - Man, Isle of, 1869, 1895, 1953 (Box 90)
    - Manchester, 1792-1951 (Box 90)
    - Manchester Round: FB correspondence and notes, 1947-1972 and undated (Box 90)
    - Manchester Round: Marmaduke Riggall correspondence, 1926, and notes on Manchester Conference of 1765 (Box 91)
    - Manchester Round: Marmaduke Riggall transcripts of Manchester Society Accounts, 1752-1773 (Box 91)
    - Manners, Lady Robert, and Nicholas--transcriptions and photocopy, 1755-1756, 1801 (Box 91)
    - Manning, Rev. Charles--transcriptions, 1748 and undated (Box 91)
    - Manse, 1948, 1950, and undated (Box 91)
    - Mansfield, 1936, 1950-1951, and undated (Box 91)
    - Manuscripts Examined, 1958-1960 (Box 91)
    - Manuscripts, Early American Methodist--notes, undated (Box 91)
    - Maps, 3 folders (Box 91)
      Includes dealer catalogs, souvenir postcards, and city plans (undated clippings).
    - March, Jane Catherine, 1758-1781, 1793-1805, 1825, 1988-1989, and undated (Box 91)
      FB correspondence and notes; photocopies of March letters to JW, 1766, and to Mrs. Ryan, ca. 1758-1767.
    - Marriage, 1748-1749, 1994, 1996 (Box 91)
    - Marriage, 1756, 1765, 1833-1898, 1945-1959, 1977-1979, and undated, 2 folders (Box 91)
    - Marriott, Frank, 1977 (Box 92)
    - Marsden, George, 1815, 1830, 1844 (Box 92)
    - Marshall, Nancy, 1772-1777 (Box 92)
      Typed and handwritten transcriptions (not by FB) of letters to Mrs. Christopher Hopper; originals in Garrett Theological Seminary and private collection of S.W. Gough.
    - Martindale, Miles and Margaret, 1796, 1824-1825 (Box 92)
    - Maskew, Jonathan, 1798 and undated (Box 92)
      Notes; original excerpt from Arminian Magazine.
    - Mason, John, 1831, 1844, 1862, 1977, and undated (Box 92)
    - Mather, Alexander, 1763-1801, 1935, 1951 (Box 92)
    - Mather, Ralph--notes and transcriptions, 1773-1775 and undated (Box 92)
    - Maxfield, Thomas--FB correspondence, notes, and transcriptions--1742, 1969-1971, and undated (Box 92)
    - Maxwell, Lady, 1816 and undated (Box 92)
      Notes, printed material, and original excerpt from The Methodist Magazine.
    - McGeary, John--notes, undated (Box 92)
    - Medallions, 1836, 1968 (Box 92)
    - Medicine, JW, Methodists and, 1786, 1953-1980, and undated (Box 92)
    - Meggott, Samuel--notes, 1764, 1875, and undated (Box 92)
    - Membership, 1757-1785, 1842, 1872, 1935, and undated (Box 92)
    - Membership, 1872-1882, 1934, 1948-1967, and undated (Box 92)
    - Memorials, World Wars I and II, 1939-1945 (Box 92)
    - Men, 1947-1949 (Box 92)
    - Meriton, John, 1900, 1990, and undated (Box 92)
      FB correspondence and notes; article on Meriton by Richard Butterworth, 1900.
    - Methodism Overseas, 1946-1947 (Box 92)
    - Methodism, miscellaneous references--correspondence and notes, 1949 and undated (Box 92)
    - Methodist Community, undated (Box 92)
    - Methodist Heritage Fellowship, 1978-1986 (Box 92)
    - Methodist Historical Treasure, 1963 (Box 92)
    - Methodist History, 1963-1964 (Box 92)
    - Methodist Homes for the Aged, 1947 (Box 92)
    - Methodist Hymn Book, undated (Box 92)
    - Methodist letters, 20th century, 1898-1960 and undated (Box 92)
      Approximately fifty letters on miscellaneous topics, of which about half are to or from Baker, dating from the late 1940s and after. Earlier letters are to and from various parties, perhaps officers in the Wesley Historical Society. Writers include Thomas Riley, Thomas Brigden, Thomas Barratt, and Marmaduke Riggall.
    - Methodist Ministers Withdrawing, 1944-1945 (Box 92)
    - Methodist New Connexion, 1949 and undated (Box 92)
    - Methodist Publishing House, London, 1986 and undated (Box 92)
    - Methodist Quarterly Review, 1979-1980 (Box 92)
    - Methodist Recorder, 1947-1969 (Box 92)
    - Methodist Sacramental Fellowship, 1946-1953 (Box 93)
    - Methodist sects, 1853-1855, 1952 (Box 93)
    - Methodist Study Centre, 1937, 1946, and undated (Box 93)
    - Methodist Union Catalog--correspondence, 1967-1982 and undated (Box 93)
    - Methodist Unions, 1947-1948 (Box 93)
    - Methodist worship, undated (Box 93)
    - Methodist Youth Department, 1946-1952, and undated (Box 93)
    - Microfilms: Duke queries pending, 1964-1969 and undated, 2 folders (Box 93)
    - Microfilms: Duke Received, 1777, 1964-1975, and undated (Box 93)
    - Microfilms: Duke requests, 1964-1968 and undated (Box 93)
    - Microfilms: Epworth, 1965-1969 and undated (Box 93)
    - Microfilms: Frank Baker's, 1950, 1961-1968, and undated (Box 93)
    - Microfilm: Harvard, 1756, 1964-1966 (Box 93)
    - Microfilms: Manuscripts, 1966-1967, 1988, and undated (Box 93)
    - Microfilms: Methodist Archives, 1964-1970 and undated (Box 93)
    - Microfilms: To order, undated (Box 94)
    - Middlesex, 1959 (Box 94)
    - Middleton, 1760, 1990 (Box 94)
    - Middleton, Lancelot, 1892, 1898, 1953, and undated (Box 94)
    - Millennium and Wesley, 1989 (Box 94)
    - Millennium, 1921, 1947-1949, 1960-1964, 1971, and undated (Box 94)
    - Milner, John, undated (Box 94)
    - Miners, 1952 (Box 94)
    - Ministerial Training, 1943-1954, 1984, and undated (Box 94)
    - Missions, 1909-1927, 1949-1957, 1983, and undated, 2 folders (Box 94)
    - Mitchell, Thomas, 1760 (Box 94)
    - Montogmery, undated (Box 94)
    - Moore Family, 1783-1788, 1951, 1989, and undated (Box 94)
    - Moore, Henry, 1793, 1802-1852, 1897, 1950 (Box 94)
    - Moorhouse, Michael, 1958-1959 (Box 94)
    - Moravian, 1727, 1757, 1960, 1989-1995, and undated (Box 94)
    - Moravian Archives, 1969-1989 (Box 94)
    - Moravian Church Archives Book, Muswell Hill, London (photocopy) 1741-1974, 1741-1974 (Box 94)
    - Moravian Letter List - 18th Century from London Archives 85-1b and Dublin 156, undated (Box 95)
    - Moravianism, 1847, 1886, 1940-1963, 1973, 1987-1989, and undated (Box 95)
    - Moravians: A Register of Members of the Moravian Church (1727-1754), by Rev. Abraham Reincke, 1873 (Box 95)
    - Morgan, James, undated (Box 95)
    - Morgan, Thomas Judson, undated (Box 95)
    - Morley, George, 1804, 1829, 1838 (Box 95)
    - Mormons, 1971 (Box 95)
    - Morris, 1949-1950 (Box 95)
    - Mort, Rev. James, undated (Box 95)
    - Mortimer (Ritchie), Elizabeth, 1777-1781, 1934-1935, 1949, and undated (Box 95)
    - Muggleton, Lodowick, undated (Box 95)
    - Murlin, John, 1749-1781 and undated (Box 95)
    - Murray, Grace, 1862 (Box 95)
      Narrative of a Remarkable Transaction in the Early Live of John Wesley, from an Original Manuscript in His Own Handwriting, Never Before Published; to Which is Added a Review of the Work, by the Rev. Joseph Hunter, 2nd ed. London: John Russell Smith, 1862. Presented as by JW, a narrative of his courtship of Grace Murray, later Mrs. John Bennet. Duplicate of copy in Duke Libraries.
    - Music, 1742, 1877, 1949-1969, and undated (Box 95)
    - Music, 1782, 1884, 1897, 1909, 1944, 1952, 1987, and undated (Box 95)
    - Myles, Catharine and William, 1797, 1814, 1831 (Box 95)
    - Mystics, 1980-1981 (Box 95)
    - Names, 1841, 1853, 1946-1952, and undated (Box 95)
    - Navy, 1756 (Box 95)
    - Negroes, 1946 [Baker's original folder title] (Box 95)
    - Nelson, John (1707-1774), 1758, 1771, 1924, 1949-1950, and undated (Box 95)
      Transcriptions of two lengthy letters to Charles Wesley, 1758; detailed notes on Nelson's itinerary, 1737-1744, and his appearances in Illingworth diary; research on his hymns; images of Nelson and related sites; Baker's correspondence; and clippings. Related materials: for additional correspondence with Charles Wesley, see also Nelson notebook filed in Wesley Family Subseries, John Wesley folder group.
    - Nelson, John (Primitive Methodist), 1822-1827 (Box 95)
      Fourteen transcribed letters to William Rodgers from Primitive Methodist preacher John Nelson (fl. 1820s, Sheerness and Whitehaven), not to be confused with John Nelson (1707-1774).
    - New Birth, 1988-1989 (Box 95)
    - New Jersey, 1962-1973 (Box 95)
    - New Walsingham, 1956-1966 (Box 95)
    - New York, 1963-1965, 1970-1974, and undated (Box 95)
      Includes draft of Baker article Early American Methodism: a Key Document, circa 1963, about the Thomas Taylor letter to John Wesley of April 11, 1768.
    - New York Priority, correspondence and report, 1923-1926, 2 folders (Box 96)
      Extensive correspondence from A. B. Sanford to [John?] Simon on the debate between New York and Maryland about the earliest establishment of the Methodist church in America.
    - New Zealand, W.P., 1940-1951, 1971 (Box 96)
    - Newcastle, 1745, 1788-1790, 1843-1872, 1919, 1940-1969, 1982, and undated (Box 96)
    - Newman, Rev. Leslie, 1948 (Box 96)
    - Newspapers, 1963, 1978, and undated (Box 96)
    - Newton, Dr. Robert, 1809-1825, 1833-1854, 1878, 1893, 1954, and undated (Box 96)
    - Newton, John, 1748-1784, 1942, 1956-1959, 1986, 1992, and undated (Box 96)
    - Newtonian Optics, undated (Box 96)
    - Nichols Literary Anecdotes, 1700-1799 (Box 96)
    - Niemoller, Martin, 1984 (Box 96)
    - Nitschmann, David, 1886 (Box 96)
    - Northampton, 1947, 1951, and undated (Box 96)
    - Northumberland, 1950 (Box 96)
    - Norwich booktrade, 1947, 1972-1981 (Box 96)
    - Norwich, 1949-1956, and undated (Box 96)
    - Nottingham, 1947-1975 (Box 96)
    - Oddie, James, 1812 and undated (Box 96)
    - Oglethorpe, General James, 1903, 1923, 1956-1975 (Box 96)
    - O'Kelly, James, 1972, 1983, 1991 (Box 96)
    - Okely, Francis, 1760, 1789, and undated (Box 96)
    - Old Newland, 1955 (Box 96)
    - Olivers, Thomas, 1744, 1763-1797, and undated (Box 97)
    - Open Air, 1932-1949 (Box 97)
    - Orders of Service 1, 1854, 1857, 1932-1960, and undated (Box 97)
    - Orders of Service 2, 1947-1977, and undated, 2 folders (Box 97)
    - Orders of Service 3, 1938-1990 and undated, 2 folders (Box 97)
    - Ordinations, 1761-1792, 1814-1837, 1867, 1898, 1914, 1947-1989, and undated (Box 97)
    - Ordinations, 1934-1982 and undated (Box 97)
    - Ordinations, Wesley, 1784-1788, 1867, 1914, 1960, and undated (Box 98)
    - Ornaments, New, undated (Box 98)
    - Ornaments, undated (Box 98)
    - Orpe, William, 1766-1767, 1849, 1866, 1897, 1934, 1947 (Box 98)
    - Orthodoxy, Greek, 1969 (Box 98)
    - Osborn Family, 1798, 1834-1843, 1872, 1948 (Box 98)
    - Otterbein, 1823 and undated (Box 98)
    - Otterbein, Philip William, 1867, 1972, 1987, 1995 (Box 98)
    - Ouseley, Gideon, 1950-1952, 1957 (Box 98)
    - Outler, Albert, 1974, 1989 and undated (Box 98)
    - Overseas Friendship League, 1945-1949, 1961 (Box 98)
    - Owen, Thomas, 1801 and undated (Box 98)
    - Oxford Annals and Persons, 1721-1737 (Box 98)
    - Oxford Institute, 1982: Wesley Studies, FB, Albert Outler, 1981-1988 and undated (Box 98)
    - Oxford Institute, Wesley: Interested People, etc., 1981-1988 and undated (Box 98)
    - Oxford, 1726, 1854, 1866-1867, 1949-1952, 1967, and undated (Box 98)
    - Oxford, 1729-1771, 1808, 1966-1977, 1988, and undated (Box 98)
    - Oxford, Methodists, 1729-1740, 1848, 1955, and undated (Box 98)
    - Oxfordshire, 1951, 1959, and undated (Box 98)
    - Paper, 1785-1789, 1952, and undated (Box 98)
    - Parish Registers, 1910 and undated (Box 98)
    - Parker, William, 1766-1770 (Box 98)
    - Parliament, 1747, 1768-1775, 1780, 1964, and undated (Box 98)
    - Pascal, 1737 (Box 99)
    - Pastoral Care, 1949, 1975 (Box 99)
    - Pawson, John, 1773-1781, 1806 (Box 99)
    - Pearsall, Rev. Richard, undated (Box 99)
    - Peckham Methodism, 1984 (Box 99)
    - Peet, G.T., 1952 (Box 99)
    - Penance, 1758 (Box 99)
    - Pentecostalists, 1959 (Box 99)
    - Periodicals, 1952-1966, 1981-1982, and undated (Box 99)
    - Periodicals: Duke, undated (Box 99)
    - Perrin, Sarah, 1740-1743, 1750-1751, and undated (Box 99)
    - Perronet Family, 1742-1799, 1802, 1826, 1848, 1868, 1902, 1928, 1946-1960, 1985, 1993, and undated (Box 99)
    - Persecution, undated (Box 99)
    - Peterson, William, 1841 (Box 99)
    - Philadelphia, 1743, 1917, 1952-1970, 1992, and undated (Box 99)
    - Philadelphia, 1942, 1956, 1969, 1975, and undated (Box 99)
    - Phillips Family, undated (Box 99)
    - Piers, Rev. Henry, 1740-1742, 1902, 1950, and undated (Box 99)
    - Pietism, 1961 and undated (Box 99)
    - Pill -- Wesley lease, Coke sails to America, 1776, 1983-1984, and undated (Box 99)
    - Pilmore, Joseph, 1769-1787, 1968-1976, and undated (Box 99)
    - Pine, William, 1782-1785, 1976, and undated (Box 99)
    - Pirates, undated (Box 99)